{"data":[{"question":"Most of Dan's time ___ writing editorials.","a":"are spent","b":"is spent","c":"was spending","d":"were spent","answer":"2","explain":"- With words that indicate portions - percent, fraction, part, majority, some, all, none, remainder, and so forth - look at the noun in your of phrase (object of the preposition) to determine whether to use a singular or plural verb. If the object of the preposition is singular, use a singular verb. If the object of the preposition is plural, use a plural verb\u00a0\n- Dan's time: singular noun \n- Simple present tense: express habit or repeated things","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"74","subcategorylv2":"35","type":"1"},{"question":"A professor and a writer ___ present at the seminar.","a":"is","b":"was","c":"were","d":"had been","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Use a plural verb with two or more subjects when they are connected by and.","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"74","subcategorylv2":"35","type":"1"},{"question":"The pair of pants _________ worn out.","a":"have been","b":"are","c":"were","d":"has been","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Subject( a pair) is singular \n- Present perfect tense: We use the Present Perfect to say that an action happened at an unspecified time before now","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"74","subcategorylv2":"35","type":"1"},{"question":"The majority of the students ___ to the teacher attentively.","a":"is listening","b":"are listening","c":"is listened","d":"are listened","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Subject ( the majority of the students) is plural noun \n- Present continuous: express the idea that something is happening now, at this very moment","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"74","subcategorylv2":"35","type":"1"},{"question":"The pros and the cons each _________ own ideas.","a":"have his","b":"has their","c":"has her","d":"have their","answer":"4","explain":"\n- If the word \"each\" comes before a compound subject, use the singular. \n ex: each boy and girl has flowers. \n- If the word \"each\" comes after a plural subject, use the plural verb \n ex: boys and girls each have flowers. ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"74","subcategorylv2":"35","type":"1"},{"question":"An wood and plastics works, with some satellite factories,___ to be built here.","a":"are","b":"is","c":"were","d":"will be","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Works - a building or group of buildings in which goods are produced in large quantities or an industrial process happens \n- An - singular","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"74","subcategorylv2":"35","type":"1"},{"question":"500 million dollars ___ a large sum of money.","a":"were","b":"are","c":"is","d":"seem","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Use a singular verb with sums of money or periods of time.","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"74","subcategorylv2":"35","type":"1"},{"question":"30 kilometers _________ a long way to travel.","a":"are","b":"were","c":"seem to be","d":"is","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Subject (30 kilometers) acts as singular","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"74","subcategorylv2":"35","type":"1"},{"question":"Eight plus thirteen ___ twenty-one.","a":"make","b":"makes","c":"are making","d":"is making","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Subject (eight plus thirteen) acts as singular","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"74","subcategorylv2":"35","type":"1"},{"question":"There are two roads and either ___ to the city hall.","a":"is leading","b":"are leading","c":"leads","d":"lead","answer":"3","explain":"- Two singular subjects connected by either\/or or neither\/nor require a singular verb","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"74","subcategorylv2":"35","type":"1"}]}